# RAHUL T. NAHARKAR (1) Featured

Developer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Spring Boot, JavaScript, Hibernate, Eclipse, Maven, HTML, CSS, Git



Current Designation: Java Developer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Sasken Technologies Ltd Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: M.Tech [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Java/Software Developer, Software Development, Spring Boot, OOPS, Design

Patterns, Hibernate, SQL, Microservices, Eclipse, Maven, HTML, CSS, Git, Software, Marchael, Grandel and GrandelEngineering, Java, Spring, JPA, RDBMS, Postgresql, Rest, Spring Mvc, Core Java

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

### Summary

Having total of 3 years' experience in Java/j2ee. And Frameworks like Spring MVC and Spring Boot.

Working as Java Developer in Sasken Technologies Ltd from june 2017. Deputed to client location Cisco System Inc Bangalore Since June 2018.

Experience in working on Spring MVC to develop monolithic web applications.

Experience in Developing micro-services using Spring Boot framework.

Experience in writing queries of elasticsearch database. And having experience of integrating Elasticsearch with spring boot framework.

Worked with postgreSQL and mysgl DB.

Having basic knowledge of angular.

## Work Experience

#### Sasken Technologies Ltd as Java Developer

Jun 2017 to Till Date

Duration :- Feb 2020 till date Role :- Design and Development Description :-

Sec is a platform for trainee in a Sasken to learn and enhance foundational and specialization competencies. It enables continuous learning and improvement of technical capabilities by providing a dashboard of trainee with his/her learning journey or training details

Involved in designing database schema

Involved in designing the flow of the application

Designed and developed the restful API

AFM is an intelligent automation tool, having the ability to automatically analyze situations and

proactively correct errors in a way that is similar to, yet much faster and more accurate than if performed manually. Responsibility:-

Designed and developed RestFul web services on Spring Boot framework, using elasticsearch queries.

Written gueries on postgreSQL

Written unit test cases using Junit

Involved in designing the flow of the application

3. Cisco CX-Portal -Syslog Client : - Cisco System Inc. Duration :- Jan 2019 to Aug 2019 Role :- Design and development Description :-

Cisco CX-portal, built on collaborative intelligence brings together all information and services about a product into one view, a single pane of glass. CX Portal shows device information and alerts, allows the customer to request Cisco services. Syslog is a tool where the logs generated by network devices were getting mapped with the cause of problem.

Developed RestFul web services on Spring Boot framework, using complex elasticsearch queries.

Written elasticsearch queries using Kibana.

Written unit test cases using Junit

Duration:- june-2018 to Dec 2018

Role: - Maintenance and Development Description :-

SORA is a legacy CISCO dashboard tool for assisting NC engineers to monitor and regulate various network components bugs reported by the end user in the market, syncing with QDDTS and CDETS bug sources. SLM is a step toward enhancing the UI experience of the SORA user with functionality improvements.

Responsibility:-

Building SLM web application using Java/J2ee technologies.

Participating on development as well as integration of and enhancements to existing products (SORA).

Bug fixing and supporting existing websites

Designed and developed restful services, core services and data access layer.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from S. B. Jain Institute of Technology Managment and Research, Nagpur in 2014

PG: M.Tech (Computers) from Department of Computer Science and information technology, Aurangabad in 2016

#### IT Skills

| Skill Name                         | Version Last Used Experience |
|------------------------------------|------------------------------|
| Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, MySQL   |                              |
| Java, J2EE, Eclipse, Apache Maven, |                              |
| Filezilla, Tomcat, Git,            |                              |
| Spring MVC, Hibernate, SpringBoot  |                              |
| HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT              |                              |

## Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English  |             |      |       |       |
| Hindi    |             |      |       |       |
| Marathi  |             |      |       |       |

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time